<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>martial arts on www.khaskarate.com</title>
    <link>https://khaskarate.com/categories/martial-arts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in martial arts on www.khaskarate.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://khaskarate.com/categories/martial-arts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2023 class schedule</title>
      <link>https://khaskarate.com/blog/newschedule2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaskarate.com/blog/newschedule2023/</guid>
      <description>updated class schedule for 2023 and the near future Beginning May 1, 2023 Class schedule Junior class/Beginning students (8 and under) Day Times Tuesday, Thursday 5:00 - 5:45 PM 8 years and up Day Times Tuesday, Thursday 6:00 - 7:00 PM Saturday 10:00 AM - 11:15 AM 8 years and up / Green belts and up Day Times Monday, Wednesday 6:15 - 7:30 PM Saturday 10:00 AM - 11:15 AM Adult class Day Times Monday, Wednesday 7:45 - 9:00 PM Private lessons, Family classes Day Times upon request upon request Orientation for new students Day Times Will be scheduled as needed Will be scheduled as needed Additional:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Best Builder</title>
      <link>https://khaskarate.com/blog/thebestbuilder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaskarate.com/blog/thebestbuilder/</guid>
      <description>The Best Builder The richest landowner in the village who made so much money in his career and decide to retire. He looked for the best builder in the city to build a house.
He came across one and the best builder who also decided to build one more house before he retired. Both seemed to be a perfect match for each other.
Both agreed on pricing and construction schedule.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The scholar &amp; ferryman</title>
      <link>https://khaskarate.com/blog/scholarandferryman/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaskarate.com/blog/scholarandferryman/</guid>
      <description>The scholar &amp;amp; ferryman The scholar got on a small boat and asked a young ferryman to take him a cross a river.
The scholar started the conversation.
&amp;ldquo;Do you know history?&amp;rdquo;, asked the scholar &amp;ldquo;I am sorry no&amp;rdquo;, replied the ferryman
&amp;ldquo;Do you know geographic?&amp;rdquo;, asked again the scholar &amp;ldquo;I am sorry no&amp;rdquo;, replied again the ferryman
&amp;ldquo;Do you know fortune telling?&amp;rdquo;, asked again the scholar &amp;ldquo;I am sorry no&amp;rdquo;, replied the ferryman</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Black Belt Test Nov 2022</title>
      <link>https://khaskarate.com/blog/blackbelttest112022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaskarate.com/blog/blackbelttest112022/</guid>
      <description>Hello everyone, I just wanted to confirm the Nov. BB test details.
The test will be held Sat. Nov. 5, 10a, at Atlee Rec.
The candidates that will test are:
Luke Hajacos - to 1st Dan
Trey Choiunard - to 1st Dan
Sensei Mark Wilds - to 3rd Dan
Trey has a conflict with the Nov. 5 date and will be tested in class on Tues. Nov 1.
Luke and Sensei Mark will test on Nov.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Message from Master Thinh</title>
      <link>https://khaskarate.com/blog/karate-group-class-and-test-2022-message-from-master-thinh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaskarate.com/blog/karate-group-class-and-test-2022-message-from-master-thinh/</guid>
      <description>Message from Master Thinh Dear Silkisondan Masters, Instructors, Black Belts, and Students:
I can’t even begin to tell you how much I look forward to seeing every one of you today. I have to take my wife to Vietnam to attend her father’s funeral. We lost him to lung cancer on Wednesday, March 16.
Vietnam is where I originally come from. I grew up and finished high school in 1970 and went to the US on April 27, 1971, as one of the few selected elite students for college education.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Full Awareness</title>
      <link>https://khaskarate.com/blog/full-awareness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaskarate.com/blog/full-awareness/</guid>
      <description>Full Awareness After ten years of apprenticeship, Tenno achieved the rank of Zen teacher. One rainy day, he went to visit the famous master Nan-in. When he walked in, the master greeted him with a question, &amp;ldquo;Did you leave your wooden clogs and umbrella on the porch?&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Yes,&amp;rdquo; Tenno replied.
&amp;ldquo;Tell me,&amp;rdquo; the master continued, &amp;ldquo;did you place your umbrella to the left of your shoes, or to the right?&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working Hard</title>
      <link>https://khaskarate.com/blog/working-hard/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaskarate.com/blog/working-hard/</guid>
      <description>Working Hard A martial arts student went to his teacher and said earnestly, “I am devoted to studying your martial system. How long will it take me to master it.”
The teacher’s reply was casual, “Ten years.” Impatiently, the student answered, “But I want to master it faster than that. I will work very hard. I will practice every day, ten or more hours a day if I have to. How long will it take then?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Other Side</title>
      <link>https://khaskarate.com/blog/theotherside/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaskarate.com/blog/theotherside/</guid>
      <description>The Other Side One day a young Buddhist on his journey home came to the banks of a wide river. Staring hopelessly at the great obstacle in front of him, he pondered for hours on just how to cross such a wide barrier.
Just as he was about to give up his pursuit to continue his journey he saw a great teacher on the other side of the river. The young Buddhist yells over to the teacher, “Oh wise one, can you tell me how to get to the other side of this river”?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chasing Two Rabbits</title>
      <link>https://khaskarate.com/blog/obsessed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaskarate.com/blog/obsessed/</guid>
      <description>Chasing Two Rabbits A martial arts student approached his teacher with a question. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;d like to improve my knowledge of the martial arts. In addition to learning from you, I&amp;rsquo;d like to study with another teacher in order to learn another style. What do you think of this idea?&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;The hunter who chases two rabbits,&amp;rdquo; answered the master, &amp;ldquo;catches neither one.&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empty Your Cup</title>
      <link>https://khaskarate.com/blog/emptyyourcup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaskarate.com/blog/emptyyourcup/</guid>
      <description>Empty Your Cup A university professor went to visit a famous Zen master. While the master quietly served tea, the professor talked about Zen. The master poured the visitor&amp;rsquo;s cup to the brim, and then kept pouring. The professor watched the overflowing cup until he could no longer restrain himself. &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s overfull! No more will go in!&amp;rdquo; the professor blurted. &amp;ldquo;You are like this cup,&amp;rdquo; the master replied, &amp;ldquo;How can I show you Zen unless you first empty your cup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning the Hard Way</title>
      <link>https://khaskarate.com/blog/chasingtworabbits/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaskarate.com/blog/chasingtworabbits/</guid>
      <description>Learning the Hard Way The son of a master thief asked his father to teach him the secrets of the trade. The old thief agreed and that night took his son to burglarize a large house. While the family was asleep, he silently led his young apprentice into a room that contained a clothes closet. The father told his son to go into the closet to pick out some clothes. When he did, his father quickly shut the door and locked him in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning the Hard Way</title>
      <link>https://khaskarate.com/blog/learningthehardway/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khaskarate.com/blog/learningthehardway/</guid>
      <description>Learning the Hard Way The son of a master thief asked his father to teach him the secrets of the trade. The old thief agreed and that night took his son to burglarize a large house. While the family was asleep, he silently led his young apprentice into a room that contained a clothes closet. The father told his son to go into the closet to pick out some clothes. When he did, his father quickly shut the door and locked him in.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
