<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>101 Zen Stories on Kha&#39;s School of Karate</title>
    <link>/tags/101-zen-stories/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 101 Zen Stories on Kha&#39;s School of Karate</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/101-zen-stories/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Buddha</title>
      <link>/post/zen/en/013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/zen/en/013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-buddha&#34;&gt;A Buddha&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In Tokyo in the Meiji era there lived two prominent teachers of opposite characteristics. One, Unsho, an instructor in Shingon, kept Buddha&amp;rsquo;s precepts scrupulously. He never drank intoxicants, nor did he eat after eleven o&amp;rsquo;clock in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The other teacher, Tanzan, a professor of philosophy at the Imperial University, never observed the precepts. When he felt like eating he ate, and when he felt like sleeping in the daytime he slept.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Cup of Tea</title>
      <link>/post/zen/en/001/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/zen/en/001/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-cup-of-tea&#34;&gt;A Cup of Tea&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nan-in, a Japanese master during the Meiji era (1868-1912), received a university professor who came to inquire about Zen.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nan-in served tea. He poured his visitor&amp;rsquo;s cup full, and then kept on pouring.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The professor watched the overflow until he no longer could restrain himself. &amp;ldquo;It is overfull. No more will go in!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Like this cup,&amp;rdquo; Nan-in said, &amp;ldquo;You are full of your own opinions and speculations. How can I show you Zen unless you first empty your cup?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Mother&#39;s Advice</title>
      <link>/post/zen/en/020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/zen/en/020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-mothers-advice&#34;&gt;A Mother&amp;rsquo;s Advice&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jiun, a Shingon master, war a well-known Sanskrit scholar of the Tokugawa era. When he was young he used to deliver lectures to his brother students.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;His mother heard about this and wrote him a letter:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Son, I do not think you become a devotee of the Buddha because you desire to turn into a walking dictionary for others. There is no end to information and commentation, glory and honor. I wish you would stop this lecture business. Shut yourself up in a little temple in a remote part of the mountain. Devote your time to meditation and in this way attain true realization.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Announcement</title>
      <link>/post/zen/en/007/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/zen/en/007/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;announcement&#34;&gt;Announcement&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tanzan wrote sixty postal cards on the last day of his life, and asked an attendant to mail them. Then he passed away. The cards read:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am departing from this world.&#xA;This is my last announcement.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tanzan&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;27 July 1892.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Great Waves</title>
      <link>/post/zen/en/008/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/zen/en/008/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;great-waves&#34;&gt;Great Waves&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the early days of the Meiji era there lived a well-known wrestler called O-nami, Great Waves.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;O-nami was immensely strong and knew the art of wrestling. In his private bouts he defeated even his teacher, but in public was so bashful that his own pupils threw him.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;O-nami felt he should go to a Zen master for help. Hakuju, a wandering teacher, was stopping in a little temple nearby, so O-nami went to see him and told him of his trouble.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Happy Chinaman</title>
      <link>/post/zen/en/012/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/zen/en/012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;happy-chinaman&#34;&gt;Happy Chinaman&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anyone walking about Chinatowns in America will observe statues of a stout fellow carrying a linen sack. Chinese merchants call him Happy Chinaman or Laughing Buddha.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This Hotei lived in the T&amp;quot;ang dynasty. He had no desire to call himself a Zen master or to gather many disciples about him. Instead he walked the streets with a big sack into which he would put gifts of candy, fruit, or doughnuts. These he would give to children who gathered around him in play. He established a kindergarten of the streets.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If you Love, Love Openly</title>
      <link>/post/zen/en/005/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/zen/en/005/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;if-you-love-love-openly&#34;&gt;If You Love, Love Openly&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Twenty monks and one nun, who was named Eshun, were practicing meditation with a certain Zen master.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Eshun was very pretty even though her head was shaved and her dress plain. Several monks secretly fell in love with her.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of them wrote her a love letter, insisting upon a private meeting.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Eshun did not reply. The following day the master gave a lecture to the group, and when it was over, Eshun arose. Addressing the one who had written her, she said: &amp;ldquo;If you really love me so much, come and embrace me now.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is That So?</title>
      <link>/post/zen/en/003/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/zen/en/003/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;is-that-so&#34;&gt;Is That So?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Zen master Hakuin was praised by his neighbors as one living a pure life.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A beautiful Japanese girl whose parents owned a food store lived near him. Suddenly, without any warning, her parents discovered she was with child.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This made her parents very angry. She would not confess who the man was, but after much harassment at last named Hakuin. In great anger the parents went to the master. &amp;ldquo;Is that so?&amp;rdquo; was all he would say.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Muddy Road</title>
      <link>/post/zen/en/014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/zen/en/014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;muddy-road&#34;&gt;Muddy Road&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tanzan and Ekido were once traveling together down a muddy road. A heavy rain was still falling. Coming around a bend, they met a lovely girl in a silk kimono and sash, unable to cross the intersection. &amp;ldquo;Come on, girl,&amp;rdquo; said Tanzan at once. Lifting her in his arms, he carried her over the mud.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ekido did not speak again until that night when they reached a lodging temple. Then he no longer could restrain himself. &amp;ldquo;We monks don&amp;rsquo;t go near females.&amp;rdquo; He told Tanzan, especially not young and lovely ones. It is dangerous. Why did you do that?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Heart Burns Like Fire</title>
      <link>/post/zen/en/022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/zen/en/022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-heart-burns-like-fire&#34;&gt;My Heart Burns Like Fire&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Soyen Shaku, the first Zen teacher to come to America, said: &amp;ldquo;My heart burns like fire but my eyes are as cold as dead ashes.&amp;rdquo; He made the following rules, which he practiced every day of his life.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the morning before dressing, light incense and meditate.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Retire at a regular hour. Partake of food at regular intervals. Eat with moderation and never to the point of satisfaction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No Loving-Kindness</title>
      <link>/post/zen/en/006/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/zen/en/006/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;no-loving-kindness&#34;&gt;No Loving-Kindness&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There was an old woman in China who had supported a monk for over twenty years. She had built a little hut for him and fed him while he was meditating. Finally she wondered just what progress he had made in all this time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To find out, she obtained the help of a girl rich in desire. &amp;ldquo;Go and embrace him,&amp;rdquo; she told her;&amp;quot; and then ask him suddenly: &amp;ldquo;What now?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Not Far from Buddhahood</title>
      <link>/post/zen/en/016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/zen/en/016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;not-far-from-buddhahood&#34;&gt;Not Far from Buddhahood&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A university student while visiting Gasan asked him: &amp;ldquo;Have you ever read the Christian Bible?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No, read it to me,&amp;rdquo; said Gasan. The student opened the Bible and read from St Mattew: &amp;ldquo;And why take ye thought for raiment? Consider the lilies of the field, how they grow. They toil not, neither do they spin, and yet I say unto you that even Solomon in all his glory was not arrayed like one of these. &amp;hellip;Take therefore no thought for the morrow, for the morrow shall take thought for the things of itself.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Obedience</title>
      <link>/post/zen/en/004/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/zen/en/004/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;obedience&#34;&gt;Obedience&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The master Bankei&amp;rsquo;s talks were attended not only by Zen students but by persons of all ranks and sects. He never quoted sutras nor indulged in scholastic dissertations. Instead, his words were spoken directly from his heart to the hearts of his listeners.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;His large audiences angered a priest of the Nichiren sect because the adherents had left to hear about Zen. The self-centered Nichiren priest came to the temple determined to debate with Bankei.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shoun and His Mother</title>
      <link>/post/zen/en/015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/zen/en/015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;shoun-and-his-mother&#34;&gt;Shoun and His Mother&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Shoun became a teacher of Soto Zen. When he was still a student his father passed away, leaving him to care for his old mother.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Whenever Shoun went to a meditation hall he always took his mother with him. Since she accompanied him, when he visited monasteries he could not live with the monks. So he would build a little house and care for her there. He would copy sutras, Buddhist verses and in this manner receive a few coins for food.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stingy in Teaching</title>
      <link>/post/zen/en/017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/zen/en/017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;stingy-in-teaching&#34;&gt;Stingy in Teaching&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A young physician in Tokyo named Kusuda met a college friend who had been studying Zen. The young doctor asked him what Zen was.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I cannot tell you what it is,&amp;rdquo; the friend replied, &amp;ldquo;but one thing is certain. If you understand Zen, you will not be afraid to die.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s fine: said Kusuda. “I will try it. Where can I find a teacher?&amp;quot; &amp;ldquo;Go to the master Nan-in,&amp;rdquo; the friend told him.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The First Principle</title>
      <link>/post/zen/en/019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/zen/en/019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-first-principle&#34;&gt;The First Principle&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When one goes to Obaku temple in Kyoto one sees carved over the gate the words &amp;ldquo;The First principle&amp;rdquo;. The letters are unusually large, and those who appreciate calligraphy always admire them as being a masterpiece. They were drawn by Kosen two hundred years ago.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When the master drew them he did so on paper, from which workmen made the larger carving in wood. As Kosen sketched the letters a bold pupil was with him who had made several gallons of ink for the calligraphy and who never failed to criticize his master&amp;rsquo;s work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Last Poem</title>
      <link>/post/zen/en/010/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/zen/en/010/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-last-poem-of-hoshin&#34;&gt;The Last Poem of Hoshin&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Zen master Hoshin lived in China many years. Then he returned to the northeastern part of Japan, where he taught his disciples. When he was getting very old, he told them a story he had heard in China.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the story:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One year on the twenty-fifth of December, Tokufu, who was very old, said to his disciples: I am not going to be alive next year so you fellows should treat me well this year.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Moon cannot be Stolen</title>
      <link>/post/zen/en/009/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/zen/en/009/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-moon-cannot-be-stolen&#34;&gt;The Moon cannot be Stolen&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ryokan, a Zen master, lived the simplest kind of life in a little hut at the foot of a mountain. One evening a thief visited the hut only to discover there was nothing in it to steal.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ryokan returned and caught him. &amp;ldquo;You may have come a long way to visit me,&amp;rdquo; he told the prowler, &amp;ldquo;and you should not return empty-handed. Please take my clothes as a gift.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Sound of One Hand</title>
      <link>/post/zen/en/021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/zen/en/021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-sound-of-one-hand&#34;&gt;The Sound of One Hand&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The masts of Kennin temple was Mokurai, Silent Thunder. He had a little protégé named Toyo who was only twelve years old. Toyo saw the olds disciples visit the masters room each morning and evening to receive instruction in sanzen or personal guidance in which they were given koans to stop mind-wandering.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Toro wished to do sanzen also.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Wait a while,&amp;rdquo; said Mokurai. &amp;ldquo;You are too young.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Story of Shunkai</title>
      <link>/post/zen/en/011/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/zen/en/011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-story-of-shunkai&#34;&gt;The Story of Shunkai&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The exquisite Shunkai whose other name was Suzu was compelled to marry against her wishes when she was quite young. Later, after this marriage had ended, she attended the university, where she studied philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To see Shunkai was to fall in love with her. Moreover, wherever she went, she herself fell in love with others. Love was with her at the university, and afterwards, when philosophy did not satisfy her and she visited a temple to learn about Zen, the Zen students fell in love with her. Shunkai&amp;rsquo;s whole life was saturated with love.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
