<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thoughts on Kha&#39;s School of Karate</title>
    <link>/tags/thoughts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Thoughts on Kha&#39;s School of Karate</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving 2024</title>
      <link>/post/2024/masther-thanksgiving-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2024/masther-thanksgiving-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dear Master Ron, Rusty, and Kha,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With Thanksgiving just around the corner and the holiday season following close behind, I want to take this opportunity to extend my warmest wishes to each of you and to all members of the Silkisondan Karate community. May you have a Happy Thanksgiving and a holiday season filled with love, peace, and blessings shared with your families.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I would also like to share the following thoughts with all members as a reminder of the importance of striving for self-improvement wherever possible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Message from Master Thinh Q4 Black belt test</title>
      <link>/post/2024/thoughts11102024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2024/thoughts11102024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dear Master, Instructors, Black Belts, and Fellow Students,&#xA;Last Saturday’s black belt test was a remarkable event to close out 2024, a testament to the hard work and dedication each of us has committed to our journeys. This occasion is truly a celebration of everyone’s commitment and growth.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Having participated in countless tests alongside Master Ron, Rusty, and Kha, I’ve come to recognize what truly stands out and what I’ve been seeking all along. While precise techniques and forms are vital, my focus goes beyond physical performance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Karate Bow</title>
      <link>/post/2024/thoughts05082024/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2024/thoughts05082024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Karate Bow&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What does it mean to bow to another student or instructor?  It means &amp;ldquo;teach me&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You bow 3 times:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;1 - When you come in&lt;br&gt;&#xA;2 - To the teacher&lt;br&gt;&#xA;3 - When you leave&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first bow means love&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The second bow means &amp;ldquo;stay calm&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The third bow means  enlightenment. Try to travel, find out how you are. Learn about yourself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts from Master Thinh</title>
      <link>/post/2023/thoughts12222023/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2023/thoughts12222023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;thoughts-from-master-thinh&#34;&gt;Thoughts from Master Thinh&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;December 22, 2023&#xA;Houston, Texas&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dear all Silkisondan Karate Students, Black Belts, Instructors and, Masters:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the year is about to come to an end, and 2024 is right around the corner, I want to congratulate Master Ron Proffitt, Master Rusty Burke, and Master Kha Nguyen for taking the leadership role to move our training quality to a different level.  Perhaps, all of these would not be possible, if there were no behind the scenes support from the spouses and other high ranking students.  My deepest appreciation goes to these individuals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts from Master Thinh</title>
      <link>/post/2023/thoughts12012023/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2023/thoughts12012023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;thoughts-from-master-thinh-draft&#34;&gt;Thoughts from Master Thinh (Draft)&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;discussion-topics&#34;&gt;Discussion topics&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-wisdon&#34;&gt;What is wisdon?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Wisdom and enlightenment is opp. Is he shy to your yourself? Wisdom you look outside? Never stop&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But best way that&amp;rsquo;s where. If you if you keep doing it, there&amp;rsquo;s some point in time you become more aware where you don&amp;rsquo;t need to take time right? So you can react immediately but how do you get there? Teach them I just say hey let&amp;rsquo;s throw a punch. Keep punching you say no that&amp;rsquo;s wrong. That&amp;rsquo;s what&amp;rsquo;s right. Yeah that&amp;rsquo;s technical but what is beyond right? Because when you teach, you don&amp;rsquo;t really ask a student right? You walk with the student too. Find the answer for them. You you know the answer for you already correct? So when you teach martial art you are actually bring yourself to them level and to be one of them. So when you practice practice for both to get to that point and keep improving if that makes sense. You can take off the events no. But he&amp;rsquo;s saying bring it bring your level to their level. So if you are black belt to so they can figure it out on their own they can walk and they own with some of your instructions. But you don&amp;rsquo;t make them like behind a stick. Force them but help them encourage them. So so how do you get to the point that you be totally awaren? That&amp;rsquo;s the that&amp;rsquo;s the question. Okay let&amp;rsquo;s say you you play this right? Yes, you practice right so you keep practicing it and sometimes you make mistakes. Sometime you play better than the other. But when do you get to the point that you feel is right? I think it&amp;rsquo;s the same as as martial arts or play tennis. Or I mean you know the professional when they serve the ball goes so quick. If you think about it you done. Just no way that you can think of that. The ball goes so fast. So what is how do you get yourself to that level? Okay, when when you think about something when you think about something do not doing fully right? You need to learn to the point you don&amp;rsquo;t need to think about. First of all, like music, right? You don&amp;rsquo;t have to memorize right? You can just play it. So the first level you learn ABC right? And after ABC you play the song and after that you keep practicing and what from there? What above that teaching because people pick you out for you to play violin in that group. There&amp;rsquo;s a reason not just put what is that? When it come to an art when it come to performance dedication thing it&amp;rsquo;s it&amp;rsquo;s the top okay. When you listen to somebody who sing is that person in that song or the song in that person? Let me hear the thing karate the same way is karate in you or you in karate? Hello Sarah, what are you? What? What do you think so karate in you so it is on your mind right? But your mind is not on crying how about if we say this? This possibility karate is not even in you and you not even in karate because if the karate in you that just memory if you in karate if you are in karate in history, you&amp;rsquo;re not in presence. Is that right? Or is not right now where I can where I can talk to you this way inside and out. Okay let me ask you this. Okay? Let me just karate is the time bound that mean you have a time factor in karate just like love right? Just like if you love your dad or your mom, you don&amp;rsquo;t you don&amp;rsquo;t say hey. I only love you from 8:00 to 9:00 8:00 p.m. Right? You don&amp;rsquo;t so so is that love in you or you in love? To get a total picture right? Or the student in you? You in all the student? Can you see it so when when you&amp;rsquo;re in front of the class when you teach you feel like you should touch all of them and all of them should be in you. So what is attention? You want a student to pay attention to you right? So what is attention? What is focus? Don&amp;rsquo;t depend on words so much because one lead to another. What is attention? Okay attention mean total total total. Whatever it is that you attend nothing else. It present not in the past tension or attendance. Attention attention. What is paying attention exactly? That mean nothing in the past. Just here they they look at you. Whatever you say, whatever you do that&amp;rsquo;s they pay attention to it right now. Nothing else. No pass. No sorry no excuse&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts from Master Thinh</title>
      <link>/post/2023/thoughts11152023/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2023/thoughts11152023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;thoughts-from-master-thinh&#34;&gt;Thoughts from Master Thinh&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A larger class moves slower.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;A smaller class moves faster.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;With a larger class, do fewer techniques. Sometimes doing less means doing more.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;on the topic of teaching, maintiaining good class rhythm and how to practice and present good technique.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts from Master Thinh</title>
      <link>/post/2023/thoughts12062023/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2023/thoughts12062023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;thoughts-from-master-thinh&#34;&gt;Thoughts from Master Thinh&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dear Silkisondan Masters:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While the end of the year is fast approaching, I wish you and your family a wonderful holiday season.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I like to share with you a few thoughts regarding meditation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What is meditation?  What does one need to meditate?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s find out the answers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Inwardly, the brain is for learning and the mind is for living.  We are our memories and memories are us. Thoughts come from memories.  When a thought arrives at your awareness, it involves a movement of time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Q and A with Master Thinh</title>
      <link>/post/2023/qamasterthinh112023/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2023/qamasterthinh112023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;q-and-a-with-master-thinh-2023-draft&#34;&gt;Q and A with Master Thinh 2023 [Draft]&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-meditation&#34;&gt;What is meditation?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-awareness&#34;&gt;What is awareness?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-mindfulness&#34;&gt;What is mindfulness?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-enlightenment&#34;&gt;What is enlightenment?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-wisdom&#34;&gt;What is wisdom?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-discipline&#34;&gt;What is discipline?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-control&#34;&gt;What is control?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-respect&#34;&gt;What is respect?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-dedication&#34;&gt;What is dedication?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-strength-and-weakness&#34;&gt;What is strength and weakness?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;and-what-is-love&#34;&gt;and what is LOVE?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-does-karate-training-mean-to-you-how-do-you-trainhardsoftboth-how-do-you-train-when-teaching-class-what-is-the-most-important-part-of-training-to-you&#34;&gt;What does karate training mean to you? How do you train(hard/soft/both)? How do you train when teaching class? What is the most important part of training to you?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-percentage-of-your-training-should-be-hardsoft-what-percentage-of-a-class-should-be-for-techniquesbasicssparringforms&#34;&gt;What percentage of your training should be hard/soft? What percentage of a class should be for techniques/basics/sparring/forms?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-do-you-run-a-class-for-kids-under-12-years-old-versus-teenage-kids-versus-adults-do-you-teach-differently-if-so-how&#34;&gt;How do you run a class for kids under 12 years old versus teenage kids? versus adults? Do you teach differently? if so, how?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-can-you-teach-karate-without-taking-so-much-time-to-talk-and-explain-techniques&#34;&gt;How can you teach karate without taking so much time to talk and explain techniques?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;when-you-teach-how-do-you-get-students-to-do-what-you-want-without-explicitly-asking-them-to-do-so&#34;&gt;When you teach how do you get students to do what you want without explicitly asking them to do so?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-minimum-standards-do-you-set-for-techniques-how-do-you-enforce-those-standards&#34;&gt;What minimum standards do you set for techniques? How do you enforce those standards?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-often-do-you-use-the-bamboo-stick-when-do-you-use-the-bamboo-stick-how-do-you-decide-who-gets-the-bamboo-stick&#34;&gt;How often do you use the bamboo stick? When do you use the bamboo stick? How do you decide who gets the bamboo stick?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-do-you-feel-about-weapons-training&#34;&gt;How do you feel about weapons training?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-are-good-womens-self-defense-techniques-to-practice&#34;&gt;What are good women&amp;rsquo;s self defense techniques to practice?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;should-you-supplement-karate-training-with-other-sports-and-activities-or-is-karate-training-enough&#34;&gt;Should you supplement karate training with other sports and activities or is karate training enough?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-do-you-feel-about-tournaments&#34;&gt;How do you feel about tournaments?&lt;/h3&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts from Master Thinh</title>
      <link>/post/2023/thoughts08212023/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2023/thoughts08212023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;thoughts-from-master-thinh&#34;&gt;Thoughts from Master Thinh&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;karate-teaching-ways-and-types&#34;&gt;Karate Teaching Ways and Types&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Silkisondan Masters:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I think this is a good time for me to share a few thoughts with you.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Karate Teaching Ways and Types:  I have seen many, probably too many.  One might ask why so many.  The right answer is that everyone is doing a little teaching everywhere.  My question to me as to what I do with my Karate teaching has always existed. Here is my reply to my question.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts from Master Thinh</title>
      <link>/post/2023/thoughts07012023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2023/thoughts07012023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;thoughts-from-master-thinh&#34;&gt;Thoughts from Master Thinh&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;kicking-with-the-back-leg-versus-kicking-with-the-front-leg&#34;&gt;Kicking with the back leg versus kicking with the front leg&amp;hellip;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The front leg is meant as a means of checking your opponent. You generate the most power using your back leg.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;reset&#34;&gt;Reset&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The thought of the reset in sparring is similar to boxers throwing a number of punches at each other and then breaking for a moment before throwing another set of punches. In karate we call this the reset. During a sparring session students should be able to exchange a number of techniques before resetting.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts from Master Thinh</title>
      <link>/post/2023/thoughts03212023/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2023/thoughts03212023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;thoughts-from-master-thinh&#34;&gt;Thoughts from Master Thinh&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts from master thinh</title>
      <link>/post/2023/thoughts01102023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2023/thoughts01102023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;thoughts-from-master-thinh&#34;&gt;Thoughts from Master Thinh&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you can control yourself, you can control anything.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Q and A with Master Thinh</title>
      <link>/post/2021/q-and-a-master-thinh-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2021/q-and-a-master-thinh-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;q-and-a-with-master-thinh-2021&#34;&gt;Q and A with Master Thinh 2021&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-do-you-think-is-the-most-impactful-part-of-karate-training&#34;&gt;What do you think is the most impactful part of karate training?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s always on my mind when you have a room full of kids and adults, men and women that come from all walks of life. They come in and do the same techinque knowing they all will be diffrent even if they look the same but on their mind and their future what they do is different.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
