<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Zen on Xe Xin So</title>
    <link>https://xexinso.com/tags/zen/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Zen on Xe Xin So</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 11:25:05 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://xexinso.com/tags/zen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Can You Make Me Obey You?</title>
      <link>https://xexinso.com/post/chapter-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xexinso.com/post/chapter-7/</guid>
      <description>The great Zen Master, Bankei, was renowned for his talks. People of all sects and ranks came to listen to him because he spoke from his heart. Bankei was much-respected and his preaching was embraced by all.
Bankei’s popularity angered a priest of another sect whose followers left to listen to Bankei. The priest wondered what it was that made Bankei gain so many supporters, especially when Bankei did not even quote from any scholarly references!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carry On</title>
      <link>https://xexinso.com/post/chapter-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xexinso.com/post/chapter-16/</guid>
      <description>Two Zen monks, Tanzan and Ekido, were traveling on a pilgrimage. It was raining heavily and the streets were muddy. As the two monks neared a bend, they saw a beautiful maiden, dressed in silk and finery, standing by the bend. Being unable to cross the muddy intersection, she stood there, staring forlornly at the road ahead.
Without hesitation, Tanzan lifted the maiden in his arms. As a shocked Ekido watched, Tanzan carried the young girl over the mud and put her down at the end of the intersection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carry On</title>
      <link>https://xexinso.com/post/chapter-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xexinso.com/post/chapter-6/</guid>
      <description>Two Zen monks, Tanzan and Ekido, were traveling on a pilgrimage. It was raining heavily and the streets were muddy. As the two monks neared a bend, they saw a beautiful maiden, dressed in silk and finery, standing by the bend. Being unable to cross the muddy intersection, she stood there, staring forlornly at the road ahead.
Without hesitation, Tanzan lifted the maiden in his arms. As a shocked Ekido watched, Tanzan carried the young girl over the mud and put her down at the end of the intersection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cause and Effect</title>
      <link>https://xexinso.com/post/chapter-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xexinso.com/post/chapter-10/</guid>
      <description>There lived an old farmer who had worked in his fields for many, many years. One day, his horse bolted away. His neighbors dropped in to commiserate with him. “What awful luck,” they tut-tutted sympathetically, to which the farmer only replied, “We’ll see.”
Next morning, to everyone’s surprise, the horse returned, bringing with it three other wild horses. “How amazing is that!” they exclaimed in excitement. The old man replied, “We’ll see.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empty Your Cup</title>
      <link>https://xexinso.com/post/chapter-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xexinso.com/post/chapter-12/</guid>
      <description>A university professor went to visit a famous Zen master. While the master quietly served tea, the professor talked about Zen. The master poured the visitor&amp;rsquo;s cup to the brim, and then kept pouring. The professor watched the overflowing cup until he could no longer restrain himself. &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s overfull! No more will go in!&amp;rdquo; the professor blurted. &amp;ldquo;You are like this cup,&amp;rdquo; the master replied, &amp;ldquo;How can I show you Zen unless you first empty your cup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is That So?</title>
      <link>https://xexinso.com/post/chapter-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xexinso.com/post/chapter-13/</guid>
      <description>A beautiful girl in the village was pregnant. Her angry parents demanded to know who was the father. At first resistant to confess, the anxious and embarrassed girl finally pointed to Hakuin, the Zen master whom everyone previously revered for living such a pure life. When the outraged parents confronted Hakuin with their daughter&amp;rsquo;s accusation, he simply replied &amp;ldquo;Is that so?&amp;rdquo; When the child was born, the parents brought it to the Hakuin, who now was viewed as a pariah by the whole village.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just Two Words</title>
      <link>https://xexinso.com/post/chapter-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xexinso.com/post/chapter-11/</guid>
      <description>There once was a monastery that was very strict. Following a vow of silence, no one was allowed to speak at all. But there was one exception to this rule. Every ten years, the monks were permitted to speak just two words. After spending his first ten years at the monastery, one monk went to the head monk. &amp;ldquo;It has been ten years,&amp;rdquo; said the head monk. &amp;ldquo;What are the two words you would like to speak?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning the Hard Way</title>
      <link>https://xexinso.com/post/chapter-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xexinso.com/post/chapter-14/</guid>
      <description>The son of a master thief asked his father to teach him the secrets of the trade. The old thief agreed and that night took his son to burglarize a large house. While the family was asleep, he silently led his young apprentice into a room that contained a clothes closet. The father told his son to go into the closet to pick out some clothes. When he did, his father quickly shut the door and locked him in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mind over Matter</title>
      <link>https://xexinso.com/post/chapter-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xexinso.com/post/chapter-9/</guid>
      <description>An accomplished though conceited young archer once dared a Zen master famed for his prowess in archery, to a test of their skills. The youth’s proficiency was extraordinary. His first arrow found its target, a far off bull’s eye, with ease; with his next shot, he split the first arrow into two.
“Think you can match that ?” he asked the old man condescendingly.
Instead of responding, the elderly monk gestured to the young man to follow him higher up the mountain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking on water</title>
      <link>https://xexinso.com/post/chapter-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xexinso.com/post/chapter-8/</guid>
      <description>Three monks sat by a lake, deep in meditation.
One stood up and said, “I’ve forgotten my mat.” Stepping on to the waters before him, he walked across to the other side, where their small hut stood. When he returned, the second monk said, “I just remembered I haven’t dried my washed clothes.” He too, strode calmly across the water to the other bank and returned in a few minutes the same way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real Power</title>
      <link>https://xexinso.com/post/chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 11:15:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xexinso.com/post/chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>During the countryside wars, a general swept from town to town, conquering each place with ease. In one particular town, the general discovered that everyone had fled just before his army arrived – everyone except the Zen master.
Curious about what sort of man this was, the general visited the temple himself. Inside, the Zen master remained still, and refused to bow or even move out of the general’s way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Tea Warrior</title>
      <link>https://xexinso.com/post/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 11:14:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xexinso.com/post/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>On a mountain lived a famous tea master. His skill in this art was unsurpassed, and many came from faraway to sit at his tea house.
One day an impatient samurai burned his tongue on the master’s green tea. Enraged, he challenged the master to a duel.
As the warrior drew his sword, the master turned to his young apprentice.
“I have done nothing but make tea my whole life. This duel is surely my end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Holy Man</title>
      <link>https://xexinso.com/post/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xexinso.com/post/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>Word spread across the country about the wise Holy Man who lived in a house atop the mountain. A young man from the village decided to undertake the difficult journey to visit him.
When he arrived at the house, an old servant opened the door and greeted him.
“I have traveled long, and now I would like to see the wise Holy Man,” said the young man.
The servant smiled and led him inside.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Full Awareness</title>
      <link>https://xexinso.com/post/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xexinso.com/post/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>After ten years of study, a monk attained the rank of Zen Teacher. One rainy day soon after his advancement, he journeyed to visit his old Zen Master.
When he walked into the house, the Master greeted him with a question.
“Tell me, did you leave your sandals and umbrella on the porch?”
“Yes,” replied the Teacher.
“And tell me,” the Master continued, “Did you leave your umbrella to the left or to the right of your sandals?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enlightenment</title>
      <link>https://xexinso.com/post/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xexinso.com/post/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>An Emperor asked the old Zen master, “What happens to an enlightened man after death?”
The master replied, “I would not know.” “But you are a Zen Master!” exclaimed the shocked Emperor. “Not a dead one!” quipped the old man.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>